# **KYLE** MORRISON | curriculum vitae

My interests and technical expertise include researching, designing, and developing extended reality experiences, simulation engineering, game design and development, empathy in virtual environments, programming languages, and digital media production.

Address: 5726 NE 38<sup>th</sup> Ave Portland, OR 97211

Phone: 573.291.8716

Email: kyle.morrison@collins.com

Web: kylecmorrison.com

## **EDUCATION**

## **Master of Fine Arts | Dramatic Media Production**

University of Georgia Graduation Date: May 2018

Current GPA: 3.99

## **Bachelor of Science | Information Technology**

University of Missouri Graduation Date: May 2015 GPA in Major: 3.258

#### **HONORS**

Nominated for Engineer of the Year – 2019 University of Missouri Deans List 2014 – 2015 University of DeVry Deans List 2009 – 2011 Best Game Athens Game Jam 2017 2nd Place UPE CS & IT Showcase 2015 3rd Place and Best Design Hack GSU 2017 Runner Up HoloHack 2016 Atlanta 3rd Place UGA Hacks 2016

#### **SKILLS**

Virtual, Mixed, and Augmented simulations and experiences with Unity and Unreal Engine C, C++, C#, Perl, Java, MEL, CSS, JavaScript, JSON, jQuery, PHP, and HTML 3D modeling, animation, and rigging with Maya and Blender Adobe Creative Suite, Microsoft Office Suite, iLife, and iWorks products

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Simulation Engineer**, Collins Aerospace

Portland, Oregon

 Using VR technologies to develop an immersive 3D virtual cockpit environment for pilots flying in a Flight Deck Simulator

- Modeling in Blender and programming in C#, C++, and Unity to link to CORESIM using UDP messages and a NetVDN
- Helping maintain and improve existing flight simulator programmed in C++ and C# with CORESIM architecture

June 2018 - Present

**3D Modeler and Programmer**, Games and Virtual Environments Lab August 2016 - May 2018 University of Georgia, Athens, Georgia Programmed VR experiments in C# and Unity Developed immersive 3D virtual environments and original software for researching influence factors, decision making, and perception **Graduate Research Assistant**, Ideas for Creative Exploration (ICE) August 2015 - May 2017 University of Georgia, Athens, Georgia Created collaborative works across multiple disciplines Facilitated collaborative projects and proposals with faculty, students, and community members Peer Learning Assistant, Introduction to Entertainment Media August 2014 - May 2015 University of Missouri College of Engineering, Columbia, Missouri Provided support for students completing projects in Adobe Photoshop and Acid Pro Graded projects and test material submitted by thirty students Audio Engineer, Voice of Literacy January 2014 - May 2015 University of Missouri College of Education, Columbia, Missouri Performed as audio technician during interviews by maintaining audio while recording audio with audacity Edited and distributed interviews for online publication by cutting audio and removing unwanted noise

## **Technical Support**, The Reflector

University of Missouri College of Education, Columbia, Missouri

- Provided technology support for all students and faculty
- Checked-out, checked-in, and serviced technology equipment and resource material
- Demonstrated creative software such as Adobe Creative Suite and iLife to five classes with an average of thirty students

**Web and Graphic Designer**, Luebbering Photography Holts Summit, Missouri

- Designed all aspects of the Luebbering Photography image
- Managed Luebbering Photography's website and the design
- Edited photos to remove blemishes and add visual effects

**Geek Squad Agent**, Best Buy Geek Squad Jefferson City, Missouri

Assisted customers with service and repair issues

Performed computer installations and technical support

February 2010 - June 2018

April 2013 – May 2015

February 2010 – July 2010

<ul> <li>HUD VR Trainer   Collins Aerospace</li> <li>Used VR technologies to develop an immersive 3D virtual cockpit environment to train on and market HUD technology</li> <li>Modeled in Blender and programmed in C#, C++, and Unity to link to CORESIM using UDP messages and a NetVDN</li> </ul>	September 2018
<ul> <li>Vaccine World   Behavioral Research VR Experiment</li> <li>Programmer and Designer</li> <li>Experiment designed to teach participants about the flu vaccine</li> <li>Designed and programmed game using C#, Unity, and Vive SDK</li> <li>Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya</li> </ul>	September 2017
Paint World   Behavioral Research VR Experiment Programmer and Designer Experiment designed to research branding effects on objects Modeled and textured objects using Autodesk Maya	November 2017
<ul> <li>Oreo World   Behavioral Research VR Experiment</li> <li>Programmer and Designer</li> <li>Experiment designed to research branding effects on object</li> <li>Designed and programmed game using C# and Unity</li> <li>Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya</li> </ul>	November 2017
Bike World   Behavioral Research VR Experiment Programmer and Designer Experiment designed to research virtual worlds distraction from pain Designed and programmed game using C# and Unity Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya	October 2017
<ul> <li>Fruit Punch!   Desktop/Mobile AR Card Game</li> <li>Programmer and Designer</li> <li>Designed and programmed game using C#, Unity, and Vuforia SDK</li> <li>Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya</li> <li>Implemented image recognition and card augmentation using C#</li> </ul>	April 2017
<ul> <li>slimGYM VR   Desktop VR Game</li> <li>Programmer and Designer</li> <li>Programmed workout simulator using C#, Unity, and Oculus SDK</li> <li>Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya</li> <li>Implemented voice controls, workout training, and NPC Al using C#</li> </ul>	April 2017
Swamp Hatch   Desktop VR Game Programmer and Designer Designed and programmed frog adventure game using C#, Unity, and Oculus SDK	January 2017

Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya

Implemented locomotion system and NPC AI using C#

## **Stickygrams | Mobile AR Application**

Programmer and Designer

- Augmented Reality application for HoloLens that allows users to leave holographic messages to their friends and the public
- Designed front-end user experience using C# and Unity.
- Placed as a runner up in Holohack 2016 in Atlanta, GA

## World Tour Z | Desktop VR Game

October 2016

December 2016

Programmer and Designer

- Programmed procedurally generated bike sim C#, Unity, and Vive SDK
- Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya
- Implemented bike and running locomotion system using C#
- Won 3<sup>rd</sup> Place at University of Georgia Hackathon

#### Mirror World | Behavioral Research VR Experiment

September 2016

Programmer and Designer

- Textured and corrected meshes on assets in Autodesk Maya
- Designed and implemented character using Fuse and Unity
- Featured project at FutureX Live 2016

## **Starboard | Desktop VR Game**

September 2016

Programmer and Designer

- Designed and programmed using C#, Unity, and Vive SDK
- Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya
- Implemented navigation system using the Vive SDK and C#
- Featured project at FutureX Live 2016

## Public Speaking Simulator | Desktop VR Experience

May 2016

Programmer and Designer

- Designed and programmed game using C#, Unity, and Oculus SDK
- Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya
- Programmed multiplayer networking architecture
- Implemented hand tracking using the Leap Motion SDK

#### **VR Maze Racing | Android VR Game**

April 2016

Programmer and Designer

- Designed and programmed a maze based strategy game using C#, Unity, and the Cardboard SDK
- Modeled, animated, and textured objects using Autodesk Maya

#### "in image of" | Video Installation

February 2016

Videographer, Animator, and Editor

- Rotoscoped and animated scenes using Adobe Photoshop
- Filmed and directed choreographed dance scenes
- Edited footage using Adobe After Effects and Premiere
- Created a Max MSP patch to control video installation

#### **UGA Graduate Acting Ensemble | Website**

January 2016

Web Developer

- Designed website for the Graduate Acting Ensemble at UGA
- Programmed site using HTML, CSS, and JSON

## **Black Lives Matter Project | Website**

Web Developer

- Designed website for an undergraduate's Black Lives Matter data visualization thesis project
- Programmed site using HTML, CSS, and JSON

#### **UniVirt | Desktop VR Experience**

May 2015

December 2015

Designer, Programmer, and Team Lead

- Led small team in creating a virtual tour of a section of campus at MU
- Modeled and textured buildings and objects using Autodesk Maya
- Designed and programmed game using blueprints, Unreal Engine, and Oculus SDK

## **VR to IRL | Windows Program**

February 2015

Designer and Programmer

- Created an application that allowed the user to switch between a windowed Oculus application and a webcam attached to the front of an HMD with gestures provided by the Leap Motion SDK
- Designed a portable solution to allow a VR workstation to be easily transported on the user's back

## **Luebbering Photography | Business Design**

**April 2011** 

Graphic and Web Designer

- Designed all aspects of the Luebbering Photography image
- Managed Luebbering Photography's website and the design
- Edited photos to remove blemishes and add visual effects

## **Book Chapters**

Kyle Morrison, Jessica McCain, and Sun Joo Ahn (2019). "Video Games and Behavior Change" In Atrill-Smith, A. *The Oxford Handbook of Cyberpsychology* (pp. 509-531). Oxford University Press.

## **Presentations**

Guest Speaker   University of Missouri XR hackathon	February 2021
Guest Lecturer   University of Missouri VR Class	October 2020
Idea Lab Conversation   Kyle Morrison	September 2020

# **Professional Development**

President   Idea Lab, UGA Interdisciplinary Student Organization	2016 – 2018
Vice President   Society for Students in Animation, UGA Chapter	2016 – 2018
Member   Georgia Game Developers Association, Athens Chapter	2015 – 2018
Member   Association for Computing Machinery, UGA Chapter	2015 – 2018
Member   Tau Sigma Honor Society, MU Chapter	2012 – 2015